Eddie Fernandez

Software Developer

Fernandezeddie54@gmail.com 253-507-3193 LinkedIn Github Website

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Applied Mathematics

Washington State University

August 2016 - May 2020 Pullman, WA

Relevant courses

- Calculus
- Differential Equations
- Mathematical Optimization
- Real Analysis
- Mathematical Computing
- Data Structures C/C++
- Program and Design C/C++
- Statistics
- Linear Algebra
- Econometrics

SKILLS

- C++
- C#
- Java
- JavaScript
- Python
- NET
- MATLAB
- MongoDB
- R, Stata
- HTML
- CSS
- Node.js
- GitHub
- Google Maps API

SUMMARY

Software Developer with a year of corporate experience and 10 years of personal experience. Knowledgeable in a wide range of development languages and methodologies. Critical thinker with proven talent for learning quickly in a results-oriented environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern

Interco.ai

May 2022 - current

- Created a demo web page that showcases 3D models in augmented reality using WebXR model viewer.
- Created an immersive AR webpage that utilizes hit tests to create objects in AR environments that can be accessed on android and IOS.
- Developed an interactive mobile web page designed to teach new restaurant employees how to assemble the ingredients of a burger.
 Used THREE.JS to render the 3d model of the burger and its ingredients.
- Developed a 3d third person shooter mini-game demo using THREE.JS which can be played on a web browser.

Software Developer

Lowkel

April 2021 - April 2022 Portland, Oregon

- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Developed software written in python to predict and optimize Lowkel delivery driver route pathing, timing, and cost.
- Created software written in JavaScript using MongoDB to correct product data at scale.
- Improved Lowkel app site search accuracy by 50% by implementing multi word query processing, stop words, result relevancy system, fuzzy search, typo correction using Levenshtein distance, and search keyword tags.
- Reduced site search result processing time from 10 seconds to 1 second. Improved Lowkel phone app design through quality assurance testing.